SAKSHAM ARORA

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

1400 Millersport Hwy • Buffalo, NY 14221 • 716-939-5841 • saksham1011@gmail.com

SUMMARY

2+ years' experience in front-end website design and development, website maintenance, and information security using several web technologies including HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript. Deep understanding of UI/UX design principles and working knowledge of responsive (mobile-first) web page design.

EDUCATION

State University of New York at Buffalo, Buffalo, NY

B.A., Computing and Applied Mathematics, December 2017

Relevant coursework: Data Structures in C++; Digital Systems; Discrete Mathematics; Introduction to Java; Numerical Analysis; Linear Algebra; Probability and Statistics; Partial Differential Equations

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Web Tools: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS, ReactJS, GitHub, Chrome Dev

tools, Wordpress

Databases: SQL, Microsoft Access

Editors: Eclipse, Visual Studio, Xcode, Pixelmator Pro, Sublime Text, Brackets

Programming Languages: Java, C++, Python, Shell, Swift **Application Software**: MS Office Suite, Adobe Photoshop

Operating Systems: Windows, Mac OS X, Linux

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Subboard, Inc., SUNY Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (January 2016 – January 2018)

Web Developer

- Conceptualized, planned, and executed original designs for a mobile responsive website www.subboard.com that helped provide information and services to new enrolled students
- Built user interface and designed overall user experience using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap for www.subboard.com
- Managed and updated Microsoft Access Database for <u>offcampushousing.buffalo.edu</u> by performing frequent updates based on user requirements and troubleshot to resolve any issues
- Developed a WebView iOS app for subboard website
- Developed a mobile app on iOS for <u>WRUB</u> (radio station for UB) to enable users to play music while the phone is locked

Subboard, Inc., SUNY Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (January 2016 – January 2018)

Network Administrator Assistant

- Supported in assembling the web server for <u>www.subboard.com</u>
- Assisted in setting up Apache server on Ubuntu to install IT ticketing system
- Assisted in setting up two tier PKI hierarchy on windows server for pharmacy to ensure better security and HIPAA compliance
- Installed printers, computers, and other computer peripherals for various Subboard department personnel

Campus Dining, SUNY Buffalo, Buffalo, NY (August 2013 – December 2015)

Student Worker

- Performed routine duties in dining hall such as food preparation, plating and serving food, verifying meal plans, cleaning kitchen and dining facilities, and stocking supplies
- Communicated and provided assistance to customers as needed

RELEVANT PROJECTS

MaxHeap - Implemented a vector-based MaxHeap data structure in C++

Sorting-Stanford-SNAP-Files – Wrote several functions in C++ to Sort/Traverse a file that stores edges of a graph in Stanford SNAP file format in C++

Scrabble Game – Implemented several functions and JUnit tests in Scrabble game for a team project in Java

Matching Game – Implemented a matching game with three different columns using swing components and event handling

Temperature Converter Application – Built a temperature converting app on iPhone using swift programming

Heat Variation Graphs – Plotted several heat and wave equations graphs using Python in Partial Differential Equations

ACTIVITIES

Participant, Hackathon (UBHacking), University at Buffalo, 2014

Member, Indian Student Association, University at Buffalo, 2013 - 2017

Member, High School Soccer team, 2012

Member, High School Badminton team, 2011

LINKS

Portfolio: https://saksham1011.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/saksham-arora-b97269131/

REFERENCES

Available upon request